Guide to the Donald Pippin Collection MUS.0003
Music Library
Donald Pippin Collection
circa 1967-2012
Music Library
Pippin, Donald
MUS.0003
370 computer file(s) 72 PDF documents; 276 TIF facsimiles; 2 MS Word 97-2003 documents; 20 video (mp4) files.
Source
The Donald Pippin Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Donald Pippin in 2013.
Biography
Born in Zebulon, North Carolina, and educated at Harvard University, Donald Pippin began his musical career as an accompanist at George Balanchine’s School of American Ballet in New York City. In 1952, Pippin moved to San Francisco, and has been an integral part of that city's artistic life since then. He did not immediately find a showcase for his talents following his move to the Bay Area. He therefore started his own recital series at North Beach's hungry i, and later at Opus One. From here, Pippin branched into small chamber ensemble presentations, working with Bay Area musicians, to present works across multiple genres, from medieval and baroque, to contemporary music, often by California composers. During the 1960s, these performances developed into a series entitled Sunday Evening Concerts, held at the Old Spaghetti Factory in San Francisco, that would become the city's primary home for chamber music.
Unexpectedly, these predominantly instrumental chamber music performances metamorphosed into vocal recitals, culminating in a number of one-act operas which became very popular with audiences at the Old Spaghetti Factory. Pippin felt strongly about making opera accessible to as wide an audience as possible and therefore started to create original English language transcriptions of each work. These translations have since become the core of Pippin's musical life, encompassing a wide range of genres, nationalities, and musical styles.
In 1975, Pippin took on his boldest move to date by presenting Verdi's little performed opera, King for a Day. From its success sprung "Pocket Opera," an organization dedicated to presenting professional performances of operatic works in intimate, intelligible productions at affordable prices. In 1977, prompted by the success of these early performances, members of the audience met and incorporated Pocket Opera as a non-profit organization.
By 1979, a subscription series was established, and the size of the audience forced the company out of the North Beach cabaret halls it had occupied and into the theaters of San Francisco. In the years since, Pocket Opera has performed an annual spring season with a growing repertory of operas. The many achievements of the company include rediscoveries, premieres, and revitalization of works long neglected--some of them previously unperformed in the United States. The Pocket Opera Press published Pippin's translations which are now performed by companies throughout the country: from San Diego to Philadelphia and from Houston to Ann Arbor. Pocket Opera's performances have been broadcast in the San Francisco Bay Area and elsewhere, some live broadcasts reaching as many as 10,000 listeners. Pippin has identified many notable singers and has been instrumental in nurturing their careers. Some singers who started with Pocket Opera have gone on to sing in major opera companies in the United States and abroad.
More information on Pippin and Pocket Opera can be found in "A Pocketful of Wry: An Impresario's Life in San Francisco and the History of the Pocket Opera, 1950s-2001" available at http://content.cdlib.org/view?docId=kt238nb0dm&brand=calisphere&doc.view=entire_text
Scope and Contents
The Donald Pippin Collection consists primarily of Pippin's numerous English translations of operatic libretto. Additional materials include facsimiles of over 300 print media reviews of Pocket Opera productions; copies of two anthologies published by Pippin, "A pocketful of lyrics" and " As the lights go up…: tales from the opera"; a speech on Offenbach given by Pippin in San Francisco in 1996; a tribute ode by Anne Dudley on the occasion of Pippin's 60th birthday; and finally an interview with Pippin published in Journal Français d'Amérique in 1996.
SDR
This is a self deposited collection in the SDR.
Pippin, Donald
- Libretto translations, 1979-2012; 71 computer file(s) 70 PDF documents
  Date information
  All dates obtained from Donald Pippin.
  Pippin, Donald
  - Donizetti Collection, 1976-2008; 10 computer file(s) 10 PDF documents
    - Anna Bolena, 1980 February 26; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Romani, Felice; Donizetti, Gaetano
    - Daughter of the regiment, 1998 July 10; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Bayard, Jean-François-Alfred; Saint-Georges, Henri; Donizetti, Gaetano
    - Don Pasquale, 1976 May 26; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Ruffini, Giovanni; Donizetti, Gaetano; Donizetti, Gaetano
    - Elixir of love, 1994 September 5; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
    - Favorite, 2008 October 5; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Vaëz, Gustave; Royer, Alphonse; Donizetti, Gaetano; Scribe, Eugène
    - Lucia di Lammermoor, 1991 October 3; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Donizetti, Gaetano; Cammarano, Salvatore
    - Lucrezia Borgia, 1996 May 14; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Donizetti, Gaetano; Romani, Felice
    - Maria Padilla, 1982 November 4; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Rossi, Gaetano; Donizetti, Gaetano
    - Mary Stuart, 1984 October 16; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Donizetti, Gaetano; Bardari, Giuseppe
    - Roberto Devereux, 1991 September 6; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Cammarano, Salvatore; Donizetti, Gaetano
  - French Collection, 1984-2012; 7 computer file(s) 7 PDF documents
    - Carmen, 1997 December 6; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Meilhac, Henri; Halévy, Ludovic; Bizet, Georges
    - Doctor in spite of himself, 1995; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Carré, Michel; Gounod, Charles; Barbier, Jules
    - Fra Diavolo, 1984 October 8; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Scribe, Eugène; Auber, D.F.E. (Daniel François Esprit)
    - Manon, 2009 September 16; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Meilhac, Henri; Massenet, Jules; Gille, Philippe
    - Romeo and Juliet, 2012 July 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Carré, Michel; Barbier, Jules; Gounod, Charles
    - Star, 1993 November 4; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Leterrier, E. (Eugène); Chabrier, Emmanuel; Vanloo, Albert
    - Soldier's tale, 1990 April 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; Ramuz, C. F. (Charles Ferdinand)
  - German Collection, 1972-1998; 10 computer file(s) 9 PDF documents
    - Abu Hassan, 1987 July 22; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Hiemer, Franz Karl; Weber, Carl Maria von
    - Apothecary, 1974 January 6; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Friberth, Karl; Goldoni, Carlo; Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
    - Coffee cantata, 1972 February 2; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750; Henrici, Christian Friedrich
    - Freischütz, 1983 October 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Weber, Carl Maria von; Kind, Friedrich
    - Martha, 1981 November 15; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Friedrich, W.; Flotow, Friedrich von, 1812-1883
    - Merry widow, 1987 October 14; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Stein, Leo; Léon, Victor; Lehár, Franz
    - Merry wives of Windsor, 1982 December 30; 2 computer file(s) 2 PDF documents
      Scope and Contents
      Two files. One contains just the translated libretto. The other contains both the translated libretto and translated narration text.
      Mosenthal, S. H. (Solomon Hermann); Nicolai, Otto
    - My fair Galatea, 1998 July 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Suppé, Franz von; Henrion, Poly
    - No love allowed, 1989 August 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883
  - Italian Collection, 1971-2010; 8 computer file(s) 8 PDF documents
    - Barber of Seville, 1990 August 2; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Sterbini, Cesare; Rossini, Gioacchino
    - Cavalleria rusticana, 2010 September 30; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Targioni-Tozzetti, Giovanni; Menasci, Guido; Mascagni, Pietro
    - Cenerentola, 1978 October 16; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Rossini, Gioacchino; Ferretti, Jacopo
    - Count Ory, 1985 November 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Rossini, Gioacchino; Delestre-Poirson, C.-G. (Charles-Gaspard); Scribe, Eugène
    - Italian girl in Algiers, 1979 September 10; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Rossini, Gioacchino; Anelli, Angelo
    - Maid promoted (Serva padrona), 1971 November 22; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Pergolesi, Giovanni Battista; Federico, Gennaro Antonio
    - Norma, 1986 November 15; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Romani, Felice; Bellini, Vincenzo
    - Secret marriage, 1990 December 26; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Cimarosa, Domenico; Bertati, Giovanni
  - Mozart Collection, 1977-1995; 6 computer file(s) 6 PDF documents
    - Abduction from the seraglio or Yanked from the harem, 1987 February 7; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Bretzner, Christoph Friedrich
    - Don Giovanni, 1995 November 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Da Ponte, Lorenzo
    - Magic flute, 1987 July 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Schikaneder, Emanuel
    - Marriage of Figaro, 1980 October 10; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
    - Mini magic flute: an entertainment for the young, circa 1987; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
    - Way of women (Cosi fan tutte), 1977 December 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
  - Offenbach Collection, 1980-2004; 9 computer file(s) 9 PDF documents
    - Bandits, 1983 September 13; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Meilhac, Henri; Halévy, Ludovic
    - Belle Helene, 1980 August 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Meilhac, Henri; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Halévy, Ludovic
    - Bluebeard, 1987 December 19; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Halévy, Ludovic; Meilhac, Henri; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
    - Cat transformed into a woman (La Chatte Metamorphosee en Femme), 1982 June 7; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Scribe, Eugène; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Mélesville, M.
    - New woman or Genevieve of Brabant, 2004 December 30; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Jaime; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Tréfeu, Etienne
    - Orpheus in the underworld, 1985 May 14; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Crémieux, Hector-Jonathan; Halévy, Ludovic; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
    - Périchole, 1983 May 10; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Halévy, Ludovic; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Meilhac, Henri
    - Tales of Hoffmann, 1997; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Carré, Michel; Barbier, Jules
    - Vie Parisienne, 1981 May 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
  - Puccini Collection, 2001-2003; 5 computer file(s) 5 PDF documents
    - Boheme, 2001 January 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF document
      Illica, Luigi; Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924; Giacosa, Giuseppe
    - Madame Butterfly, 2002 July 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Giacosa, Giuseppe; Illica, Luigi; Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924
    - Manon Lescaut, 2002 November 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Oliva, Domenico; Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924; Illica, Luigi
    - Rondine, 2001 October 2; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Adami, Giuseppe; Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924
    - Tosca, 2003 September 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
  - Slavic Collection, 1979-2009; 7 computer file(s) 7 PDF documents
    - Bartered bride, 1992 October 26; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Smetana, Bedřich; Sabina, Karel
    - Cunning little vixen, 2001 November 11; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Janáček, Leoš, 1854-1928; Janáček, Leoš, 1854-1928
    - Eugene Onegin, 1982 September 24; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich; Shilovskiĭ, K. (Konstantin)
    - Halka, 2009 October 22; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Moniuszko, Stanislaw; Wolski, W. (Włodzimierz)
    - Haunted manor, 2008 October 15; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Chęciński, Jan Konstanty; Moniuszko, Stanislaw
    - Queen of Spades, 2006 June 8; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich; Chaĭkovskiĭ, Modest Il'ich; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich
    - Two widows, 1979 September 30; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Smetana, Bedřich; Züngel, Emanuel
  - Verdi Collection, 1975-2004; 9 computer file(s) 9 PDF documents
    - Ernani, 1997 October 11; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Piave, Francesco Maria; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Falstaff, 2000 August 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901; Boito, Arrigo
    - King for a day (Giorno di regno), 1975 June 24; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901; Romani, Felice; Solera, Temistocle
    - Macbeth, 2004 October 25; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Maffei, Andrea; Piave, Francesco Maria; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Marauders (Masnadieri), 1997; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Maffei, Andrea; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Oberto, count of San Bonifacio, 2000 May 26; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
      Piazza, Antonio; Solera, Temistocle; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Rigoletto, 1993 July 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
    - Stiffelio, 1979 March 7; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
    - Traviata, 1999 July 17; 1 computer file(s) 1 PDF
- Reviews, circa 1967-2011; 274 computer file(s) 274 TIF facsimiles
  Reviews published in print media sources of numerous Pocket Opera productions.
  - Abu Hassan / Betly - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Weber, Carl Maria von; Kosman, Joshua; Donizetti, Gaetano
  - Acis and Galatea - Oakland Tribune, 1976 September 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Shere, Charles; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - Acis and Galatea - Opera Guide, 1981 August 23; 2 computer file(s) 2 TIF facsimiles
    Provoo, George; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - Acis and Galatea - San Francisco Chronicle, 1967 September 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; Commanday, Robert
  - Acis and Galatea - San Francisco Chronicle, 1972 September 12; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - Agrippina - San Francisco Chronicle, 1977 September 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Alcina - San Francisco Chronicle, 1979 August 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; Tircuit, Heuwell
  - Anna Bolena - Christian Science Monitor, 1980 July 10; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Donizetti, Gaetano; Bartlett, Kenneth E.
  - Anna Bolena - Peninsula Times Tribune, 1983 August 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Donizetti, Gaetano; Smith, Karen
  - Anna Bolena - Post, 1980 June 5; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Donizetti, Gaetano; Gereben, Janos
  - Anna Bolena - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Commanday, Robert; Donizetti, Gaetano
  - Anna Bolena - Santa Barbara News-Press, 1980 June 28; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Anna Bolena - Voice, 1980 June 20; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Ariel; Donizetti, Gaetano
  - Apothecary / King for a day, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Bladen, Barbara; Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
  - Apothecary - Peninsula Times Tribune, 1981 February 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
  - Apothecary - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Tucker, Marilyn; Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809
  - Ariodante - The Berkeley Gazette, 1984 February 7; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; Livingstone, Janet
  - Ariodante - San Francisco Chronicle, 1978 March 14; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Tucker, Marilyn; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - Ariodante - San Francsico Chronicle, 1984 January 31; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; Tucker, Marilyn
  - Ariodante - San Mateo Times, 1987 April 3; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Atalanta - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Atalanta - San Francisco Chronicle, 1982 August 17; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Tircuit, Heuwell; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - Bandits - Peninsula Times Tribune, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Ratliff, William
  - Bandits - Sacramento Bee, 1985 February 5; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Masullo, Robert A.; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Bandits - Berkeley Voice, 1985 February 13; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Livingstone, Janet; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Bandits, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Quality of copy
    Very poor quality scan. Content is mostly indecipherable.
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Barber of Seville - Opera News online edition, 2001 November 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Rossini, Gioacchino
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Chronicle, 1983 June 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Belle Helene - Opera Guide, 1981 August 16; 3 computer file(s) 3 TIF facsimiles
    Provoo, George; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Tucker, Marilyn; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - Oakland Tribune, 1981 August 17; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Shere, Charles; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - Peninsula Times Tribune, 1981 April 14; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Riese, Janice
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Examiner, 1981 March 2; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Ulrich, Allan
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Tucker, Marilyn
  - Belle Helene, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Belle Helene - Sacramento Bee, 1983 January 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Glackin, William; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - Daily Democrat, 1983 January 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Halsey, Jan; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - Bay City News Service, 1984 July 24; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Wisehart, Cynthia; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - Berkeley Voice, 1984 July 25; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Livingstone, Janet
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Chronicle, 1983 February 8; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Commanday, Robert
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Examiner, 1981 March 2; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Ulrich, Allan; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene - San Francisco Examiner, 1984 July 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Beach, Scott
  - Belle Helene, 1984 July 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Belle Helene - Davis Enterprise, 1983 January 17; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Weaver, Judy
  - Belle Helene - Prince George's County Sentinel, 1983 November 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Carter, Richard; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Belle Helene / Vie Parisienne / Bridge of sighs - Bay Area Reporter, 1984 August 2; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Karr, John F.
  - Belle Helene / Vie Parisienne / Bridge of sighs - Oakland Tribune, 1984 August 6; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Shere, Charles
  - Bluebeard, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Share, Stephen
  - Bluebeard - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Bridge of sighs - Berkeley Voice, 1984 April 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Bridge of sighs - San Jose Mercury News, 1984 January 24; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Hertelendy, Paul; Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880
  - Bridge of sighs - San Francisco Chronicle, 1984 January 24; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Cat transformed into a woman, 2001 June; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Offenbach, Jacques, 1819-1880; Lumley, Margaret
  - Cat transformed into a woman - San Francisco Examiner, 1982 July 19; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Cenerentola - San Francisco Chronicle, 1979 January 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Tircuit, Heuwell; Rossini, Gioacchino
  - Cenerentola - Spokesman-Review, 1984 October 1; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Rossini, Gioacchino; Rivers, Travis
  - Conspirators - San Francisco Chronicle, 1980 March 4; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Tucker, Marilyn; Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828
  - Cosi fan tutte - San Francisco Chronicle, 1978 June 20; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Frankenstein, Alfred V. (Alfred Victor)
  - Cosi fan tutte - Oakland Tribune, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Hertelendy, Paul
  - Cosi fan tutte - Peninsula Times Tribune, 1979 July 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Ratliff, William
  - Cosi fan tutte, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Pontzious, Richard L.; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Cosi fan tutte - Daily Californian, 1983 March 11; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Cosi fan tutte - Palo Alto Times, 1978 June 20; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Maves, C. E. (Carl); Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Cosi fan tutte - Oakland Tribune, 1978 June 21; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Hertelendy, Paul; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Cosi fan tutte - San Mateo Times, 1979 July 18; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
  - Cosi fan tutte - Peninsula Times Tribune, 1983 March 8; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Smith, Karen; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Cosi fan tutte, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Wakeland, Jeanie R.; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Count Ory, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Rossini, Gioacchino; Hill, Cynthia
  - Count Ory - San Jose Mercury News, 1986 March 19; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Hertelendy, Paul; Rossini, Gioacchino
  - Daughter of Madame Angot - San Jose Mercury News, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Lecocq, Charles; Hertelendy, Paul
  - Daughter of Madame Angot - San Francisco Chronicle, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Lecocq, Charles; Tucker, Marilyn
  - Deidamia - Tribune, 1983 August 23; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Ross, Janice; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759
  - Der Freischütz - San Francisco Examiner, 1984 February 27; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Beach, Scott; Weber, Carl Maria von
  - Dido and Aeneas - San Francisco Chronicle; Xerxes - San Francisco Chronicle, 1974 August-September; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    - Dido and Aeneas - San Francisco Chronicle, 1974 August 27
    - Xerxes - San Francisco Chronicle, 1974 September 24
  - Don Giovanni - San Jose Mercury News, undated; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Orr, Elizabeth Muñoz; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Don Giovanni - Sun-Reporter, 1996 June 6; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    Ohman, Eleanor; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Don Pasquale - Sacramento Union; Cenerentola - San Francisco Chronicle; Ariodante, circa 1978-1979; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile
    - Don Pasquale - Sacramento Union, 1978 June 26
      Donizetti, Gaetano
    - Cenerentola - San Francisco Chronicle, 1979 January 23
      Rossini, Gioacchino; Tircuit, Heuwell
    - Ariodante, undated
  - Don Pasquale - San Ramon Valley Times, 1995 March 10; 1 computer file(s) 1 TIF facsimile